## **Harshil Shah**

Website | +1 365-440-3545 | emailharshilshah@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/iharshilshah | GitHub

# **SUMMARY**

Passionate about finding insights, storytelling and presenting through visuals. Created various projects using Python, SQL, and Machine Learning. Ability to translate complex questions into understandable insights. Having experience in working with Data Glacier as a Data Analyst Intern as well as projects for my college, understanding and articulating different business models, conducting exploratory data analysis to reach important conclusions for future business growth.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### Data Analyst Intern, Data Glacier, Canada

#### Sep 2022 - Dec 2022

- It brings us 20+ years combined experience in Data Science which helps us to grow business and be creative as it believes Data will be the oxygen in 21<sup>st</sup> century.
- Analyzed organizational procedures, predicted business requirements, and revealed facts for strategy enhancement.
- Came up with strategies for cleaning data on more than 13 million entries and arranged the information in a pivot table to extract.
- Incorporate insights that helped the client promote products and boost sales by 36%.
- Exploratory Data Analysis was used to develop recommendations for the customer's upcoming corporate development, which led to a 23% increase in revenue.
- Using a variety of BI tools, presented recommendations, and addressed business solutions.

### Customer Service Representative, Fresh Co, Canada

### Oct 2021 - Sep 2022

- Serving customers by providing product and service information and resolving product and service problems.
- Attracts potential customers by answering product and service questions and suggesting information about other products and services.
- Opens customer accounts by recording account information.

## **SKILLS**

- Languages & Tools Python, NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Sci-kit Learn, Beautiful Soup, OpenCV, Keras, TensorFlow, SQL, Tableau, Power BI, Git, Postman, JIRA, Selenium, MS Word, MS Excel, MS Teams, MS PowerPoint, MS SharePoint, MS Access.
- Data Science Skills Regression (Linear, Multiple-Linear, Polynomial, SVR, Random Forest), Classification (Logistic, Naive Bayes, SVC, Random Forest, KNN), Clustering (K-means), Anomaly Detection, Deep Learning (CNN, RNN, LSTM), Hypothesis Testing.
- Other Skills Exceptional Interpersonal, Leadership, Team Management, Excellent Analytical Thinking, Problem-Solving, Prioritizing, Decision-Making, Respectful, Creative.

### **EDUCATION**

Post-Graduate Certificate, Applied A.I. Solutions Development, George Brown College, Canada Jan 2022 - Dec 2022

Graduate Certificate, Information Technology, Algoma University, Canada Jan 2021 - Dec 2021

Bachelor of Technology, Computer Science & Engineering, Parul University, India

May 2016 - May 2020